### Borja Martín Hernández

#### 685277840

# borj01ster@gmail.com

http://www.linkedin.com/in/borjamartinhernandez



### **PROFILE**

Several years of experience programming web applications, windows desktop applications, and mobile applications among others. I started programming at Rey Juan Carlos University, learning a solid basis for the rest of my career. Learned to put special care in coding, applying good practices, making efficient code, readable and easily understandable. Since then, I have worked for some of the biggest companies in the IT Sector in my country, and I have had the opportunity to learn new amazing technologies. My main skill set is oriented towards .NET technologies, and recently I have been involved in mobile development projects, using frameworks like PhoneGap or coding Native Android applications. I love improving myself, learning new skills and sharing my knowledge with others, therefore creating better results for the teams I work in. Last years I've been dedicating myself to teaching, both English and Technology in institutions such as Rey Juan Carlos University.

## **KEY ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Used Jquery Mobile to redesign web application for mobile uses, saving months of work for my company.
- Detected regions of slow code and unnecessary calls and methods, saving several seconds of loading time for the application I was working in.
- Worked hard as a team member, sharing my knowledge and trying to improve people who I worked with.
- Learned what I needed to learn to be the best programmer I can be.

## EMPLOYMENT EXPERIENCE

### **ASP.NET MVC 4 / Jquery Mobile Developer**

## **ERS (Dublin, Ireland)**

August 2014 - December 2016

Development on a web application made with ASP.NET MVC, building new functionalities and reviewing existing ones. Testing and optimizing code. Mobile Web version for application using MVC and JQuery Mobile

Technologies: ASP.NET MVC 4, JQuery, HTML, CSS3, C#, JQuery Mobile, AJAX, Visual Studio 2013, SQL Server 2008

### **ASP.NET C# Developer / Responsive Design Developer**

#### **AXA Seguros**

January 2014 - June 2014

Developed several graphic components for AXA Greece Website, using third party jquery controls like JQGrid and Bootstrap responsive design framework so the web could be available for display on any kind of device. The main technology involved was ASP.NET C#. I also had to develop communication between the client and server using Ajax and Webservices.

February 2013 - May 2013

Finished my computer science bachelor degree. I accomplished a final project involving technologies like ASP.NET, Jquery, JqueryMobile, Android, LINQ, Visual Studio 2010. The project was a mixed web/mobile application to perform studies regarding learning styles in university classrooms.

#### **ASP.NET C# Developer / Mobile Developer**

#### Accenture

June 2011-February 2013(1 year 9 months) Pozuelo De Alarcón Area, Spain

ASP.NET improvements, adjustments and maintenance duties for web application. Designed a mobile version for the application using Jquery Mobile, a jquery framework running over HTML5. New web components and graphics to display financial information. Performed backend and frontend coding using jquery and asp.net. Technologies: ASP.NET, C# , WebServices, Ajax , WCF, Jquery, JQuery Mobile, LINQ ,HTML5, CSS3, SQL Server 2008, Visual Studio 2008/2010

#### **Sharepoint Developer**

### **Alba Technology**

April 2011-June 2011(3 months) Pozuelo De Alarcón Area, Spain

Attended a course about Sharepoint 2007/2010 for two months and then moved to a sharepoint portal project for management of client company. My duties involved removing bugs and failures.

Technologies: Sharepoint 2007, Sharepoint 2010

### **PL/SQL** Developer

### **Makesoft Technologies**

January 2011-March 2011(3 months) Madrid Area, Spain

SQL procedures for massive sales management application. Application was composed of stored procedures, triggers, jobs, SQL queries to elaborate sales reports.

Technologies: PL/SQL, Oracle Relational Database

# **InControl System Documentation Technician**

## Sandoz

June 2010-January 2011(8 months) Pozuelo De Alarcón Area, Spain

In charge of Incontrol documentation for Sandoz spain. The job involved elaboration of computer systems documentation for a pharmaceutical company, along with small .NET windows forms applications.

Technologies: MonoDevelop, C#, InControl Documentation Procedures

### .NET Developer

### Indra

September 2007-July 2008(11 months)

Attended a .NET course about Windows Forms and ASP.NET for two months. ASP.NET project for two months, coding HTML web pages with javascript as client side language, then moved to a Windows Forms C# project for a military application. Design of new windows forms controls, code optimization and maintenance duties.

Technologies: ASP.NET, Javascript, Ajax, Visual Studio 2005, C#, Windows Forms, HTML

# **KEY SKILLS**

ASP.NET-C#-HTML5-Javascript-Jquery-Jquery-Mobile-PhoneGap-Ajax-WebServices-Visual Studio-2005/2008/2010-CSS3-Android

# **EDUCATION**

## **Masters Degree in Teaching**

Universidad Rey Juan Carlos

2017-2018

## **Bachelor of Computer Science**

**Universidad Rey Juan Carlos** 

2004-2013

## **PROJECTS**

## Web/Mobile Application for Learning Styles Analysis

Web Application for performing Felder-Silverman test, capture of results and an android application developed using PhoneGap and Jquery Mobile for analyzing global results.

Technologies: ASP.NET, Ajax, WebServices, LINQ, PhoneGap, Jquery Mobile, Android

# **CERTIFICATES**

## **Cambridge CELTA Certificate**

Cambridge English Language Assessment

October 2016

## **C2 Cambridge English Proficiency Certificate**

Cambridge English Language Assessment

January 2016